Guide to the United Federation of Teachers Hans Weissenstein Negatives PHOTOS 019 001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series XXV: Predecessor Union: Teachers' Guild.
  - Teachers' Guild - Pickets "Wake up Mr. & Mrs. NY", Jan 13, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1575)
  - Teachers' Guild - Fannie Hurst [Speaking (to members?) at Guild meeting.], Feb 6, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1676)
  - Teachers' Guild 25th Anniversary dinner Hotel Roosevelt, Mar 5, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1726)
  - Teachers' Guild Cara Cook [headshots] [Collection includes corresponding prints.], Mar 14, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1734)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] & K[olodny, Jules?] First Polio Shots NY School Children PS 61 ["Polio Pioneers 1954" logo on banner reading: "New York School Children Join National Field Trials of Salk Polio Vaccine"], Apr 27, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1792)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] & K[olodny, Jules?] Polio Vaccination PS 165 (Queens ) Flushing, May 4, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1811)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] & K[olodny, Jules?] Polio [Vaccination] P. S. 29 [Staten Island], Jun 11, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1895)
  - Israel Clinton Community Center Hon. Phelps Asst. Supt. Greenberg, Jun 17, 1954 (Box 1, Item 1889)
  - Teachers' Guild Roosevelt Hotel - Awards Luncheon & Panel (George Counts & John Childs Dewey Awards), Mar 5, 1955 (Box 1, Item 2292)
  - Teachers' Guild [Abe] Lefkowitz dinner Hotel Commodore, May 23, 1955 (Box 1, Item 2436)
  - Teachers' Guild Check presentation [Charles] Cogen, Dec 6, 1955 (Box 1, Item 2675)
  - Teachers' [Guild?] [NY] Public Library Tess Cohen Grafford Book, Dec 13, 1955 (Box 1, Item 2732)
  - Board of Education Public Schools Reading Clubs, Jan 30, 1956 (Box 1, Item 2802)
  - Teachers' Guild Spring Luncheon Walter Reuther & George Meany, Mar 3, 1956 (Box 1, Item 2877)
  - Teachers' Guild group head presentation, Oct 2, 1956 (Box 1, Item 3171)
  - Teachers' Guild - head/ group shots [at Guild Headquarters?] Dave Selden on guitar, Dec 27, 1956 (Box 1, Item 3357)
  - Jamaica High School Owen Engel, Jan 24, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3416)
  - Teachers' Guild meeting Trade High School, Feb 22, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3486)
  - Teachers' Guild - Luncheon Biltmore [?] (Thurgood Marshall, Dewey Award winner), Mar 2, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3472)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] K[olodny, Jules?] City Hall Teacher Presentations, May 21, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3617)
  - Teachers' Guild [meeting], May 24, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3625)
  - [Charles] Cogen, [Alice] Marsh, [Rebecca] Simonson (staff / officers), Oct 2, 1957 (Box 1, Item 3782)
  - Teachers' Guild [Two men holding sign that reads "Higher Salaries = More Teachers = Better Schools; Raise Teachers' Salaries; Work Through Your Parents Ass'n, Your Civic Club, Your Union".], Jan 7, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4603)
  - NY Teachers' Guild Headshots [Unidentified Individuals], Jan 8, 1958 (Box 1, Item 3940)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] K[olodny, Jules?] March of Dimes PS 54 check presentation, Jan 31, 1958 (Box 1, Item 3981)
  - Teachers' Guild Norman Cousins Waldorf luncheon, Mar 2, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4038)
  - Teachers' Guild Strike at Board of Education, Sep 25, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4329)
  - Teachers' Guild head shots [Unidentified Individuals], Sep 26, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4331)
  - Teachers' Guild Union Conference Astor Hotel, Oct 4, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4349)
  - C[ogen, Charles?] K[olodny, Jules?] M[arch] of D[imes] School Flyer Program City Hall Mayor Wagner Silver Theobald, Nov 6, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4444)
  - Teachers' Guild 2 Headshots [Unidentified Individuals], Dec 26, 1958 (Box 1, Item 4593)
  - Teachers' Guild - Rally @ Washington Irving HS, Feb 5, 1959 (Box 2, Item 4672)
  - Teachers' Guild Annual Conference Father George Ford, Mar 7, 1959 (Box 2, Item 4750)
  - Teachers' Guild [Includes headshot of a woman and a man at a desk with paperwork, including "Give one hour for City Hall Picket Duty" sign-up sheets in front of him], Mar 31, 1959 (Box 2, Item 4791)
  - NY Teachers' Guild Pension Meeting, Dec 4, 1959 (Box 2, Item 5249)
  - Teachers' Guild - snowy day pickets @ Board of Education, Dec 21, 1959 (Box 2, Item 5318)
  - Teachers' Guild Community Church [Headshots and men with dues information and union application.], Mar 1, 1960 (Box 2, Item 5481)
  - NY Teachers' Guild Annual Conference A. Philip Randolph Honored, Mar 5, 1960 (Box 2, Item 5489)
  - NY Teachers Elections Hotel Astor, Mar 16, 1960 (Box 2, Item 5513)
- Series XXVI: Other Teachers' Organizations.
  - AFT Collective Bargaining Conference Mr. Nicholas Zonarich AFL-CIO, Mr. C. Smith, Gary Story & Panel, undated (Box 3, Item 7821)
  - 3 Films of Amateur St. Johns Picket line [UFCT], undated (Box 6, Item 10730)
  - AFT Convention Reception, Aug 18, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7815)
  - AFT Repro for Mr. H. Caylor [of an unidentified individual], Aug 19, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7818)
  - AFT Luncheon & Awards, Journalistic, Aug 19, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7817)
  - AFT opening session speakers, Aug 19, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7816)
  - AFT Speakers Dr. Cameron, Mr. Page [?], Mr. Taylor & luncheon, Human Relations G. Fowler, Aug 20, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7819)
  - AFT Banquet Senator Jacob K. Javits & Joe Adams, Aug 22, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7825)
  - [AFT] Mr. [Carl] Megel & Mr. [Charles] Cogen & others, Aug 22, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7823)
  - [AFT] Mr. [Carl] Megel, Mr. [Charles] Cogen & others, Aug 22, 1963 (Box 3, Item 7822)
  - Empire State [Teachers' Union] Convention Forest Hills Lun[cheon?], Oct 9, 1964 (Box 4, Item 8594)
  - UFCT Picket Line St. Johns Brooklyn, Jan 4, 1966 (Box 4, Item 9502)
  - Empire State Teachers, Jan 8, 1966 (Box 4, Item 9511)
  - UFCT St. John's Queens, Jan 13, 1966 (Box 4, Item 9545)
  - Empire State Teachers, Sep 9, 1966 (Box 5, Item 10039)
  - AFT Press Conference of Overseas Press Club, Mar 6, 1967 (Box 5, Item 10354)
  - City Hall UFCT Pickets, Apr 18, 1969 (Box 7, Item 11786)
  - Empire State Teachers Jul. [?] Hotel, Oct 19, 1969 (Box 9, Item 12116)
  - Empire State Teachers [headshots], Dec 15, 1969 (Box 9, Item 12283)
  - Empire State Teachers Sheraton La Guardia, Jan 10, 1970 (Box 10, Item 12320)
  - Empire State Teachers Reception, Feb 19, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13091)
  - Israeli Teachers Union Pres. Luncheon Gramercy Park, Mar 30, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13179)
  - UFCT & Legisl. Conf., Press Conference, Mar 29, 1972 (Box 28, Item 13925)
  - College Teachers - Picket line Board of H. Education [Professional Staff Congress], Sep 13, 1972 (Box 29, Item 14085)
  - Prof. Staff Congress, Picket line, Brooklyn Comm. College, Feb 22, 1973 (Box 29, Item 14243)
  - Prof. Staff Congress, Lehman College, City College, Picket lines, Mar 27, 1973 (Box 30, Item 14288)
  - Prof. Staff Congress - Kingsboro Comm. College, Sarelik - Ruth Lerner, Mar 27, 1973 (Box 29, Item 14280)
  - Prof. Staff Congress, Kingsboro Comm. College picketing, Apr 3, 1973 (Box 30, Item 14292)
  - [Professional Staff Congress] City University Bus to Albany [with "Save Open Admissions and Free Tuition" signs], May 9, 1973 (Box 30, Item 14334)
- Series XXVII: Other Labor Organizations
  - NY Central Labor Council, Apr 8, 1964 (Box 3, Item 8231)
  - Reception Greek Freedom Fighters Central Labor Council, Mar 26, 1970 (Box 11, Item 12474)
  - Central Labor Council, Mar 19, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13156)
  - Frontlash, Apr 22, 1971 (Box 19, Item 13222)
  - Julia Richmond HS Frontlash Press Conference, May 13, 1971 (Box 21, Item 13300)
  - Central Labor Council Voter Registration, Jun 1, 1971 (Box 21, Item 13364)
  - Jewish Labor Committee on Soviet Jewry, Nov 4, 1971 (Box 24, Item 13607)
  - Central Labor Council Prize Council, Nov 17, 1971 (Box 24, Item 13644)
  - PS 304 Brooklyn Painters Picket line [Painters District Council 9 picketing], Jan 11, 1972 (Box 26, Item 13792)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, Feb 13, 1972 (Box 26, Item 13834)
  - Frontlash Exhibit & Award, Feb 22, 1972 (Box 27, Item 13868)
- Series XXVIII: Other Organizations.
  - Liberal Press Staff, May 26, 1966 (Box 5, Item 9938)
  - WBAI [A demonstration of the Jewish Defense League calling to keep Julius Lester off the air. Appears a counter-demonstration is taking place by a group called "Whites Against White Violence." Unidentified individuals being arrested by police.], Jan 29, 1969 (Box 7, Item 11628)
  - Debate Ethical Culture [Society?], Mar 28, 1969 (Box 7, Item 11749)
  - Ansonia Reform Democratic Club - Ansonia Candidates for District Leader, David Allen and Dorothy Walasek, of the 65th Assembly District Democratic primary elections, Jun 9, 1969 (Box 8, Item 11947)
  - PS 190 [National] Welfare [Rights Organization], Sep 12, 1969 (Box 8, Item 12045)
  - American Jewish Congress, Nov 9, 1969 (Box 9, Item 12181)
  - Panel Brotherhood in Action, Dec 2, 1969 (Box 9, Item 12247)
  - MES [?] conf. NCCJ [National Conference for Community and Justice], Mar 13, 1970 (Box 11, Item 12443)
  - Wartburg Lutheran Home for Aging Brooklyn, Mar 3, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13111)
  - Honest Ballot Assoc., Mar 9, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13130)
  - Accounting Division [of the Anti-Defamation League Appeal] Waldorf Astoria [presenting awards to William Bateman and Stephen Chan], Mar 24, 1971 (Box 18, Item 13171)
  - Lincoln Square Democratic Club, Jun 29, 1971 (Box 22, Item 13441)
  - Citizen Council for the Handicapped - Gramercy Hotel - Sid Harris, Oct 13, 1971 (Box 23, Item 13527)
  - Brotherhood in Action Sid Harris, 560 7th Ave., Nov 5, 1971 (Box 24, Item 13603)
  - Ethical Culture Society Building - EFC Youth in Politics, Dec 2, 1971 (Box 25, Item 13689)
  - Velma Hill Workmen's Circle, Feb 18, 1972 (Box 27, Item 13844)